Kevin G. Salinas

646.721.7856 · hello@kevingsalinas.me · https://kevingsalinas.me/

Highly motivated, passionate, and determined designer, with a background in IT technical support, user-centric issues, and website management. Proficiencies in UI design, UX design, HCI, IT management, IT infrastructure, troubleshooting hardware/software in Windows or Apple devices, and front-end development (HTML/CSS/JavaScript). Over 4 years of personal and professional experience creating websites and designing apps. Excellent analyzer and problem solver, with ability to tackle issues from multiple perspectives and create valuable solutions. Looking to bridge the gap between users and the products they use.

Capabilities include:

- XD, Sketch, InVision, Figma
- UI Design
- HTML/CSS
- Prototyping

- Adobe Suit (PS, AE, Sketch, AI, ID)
- Wireframes
- JavaScript
- System Admin

- SEO
- IT Infrastructure
- Graphic Design
- Hardware/Software Troubleshooting

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA – (2019 – Present)

Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Lab - Human Computer Interaction for User Experience Design

University at Albany, NY – (Graduated 2016)

B.S. Informatics - Human Computer Interactive Design & Social Media Analytics

Professional Experience

The Station / Music Playground / Diner Music / Audigent

Manager, IT Operations, Graphics Design, Web Developer

Jan 2019 - Present

The Station, The Music Playground, The Diner Music, and Audigent are all sister companies that fall under one umbrella. From post-production, content creation, audio design, to original music licensing, and most recently – data management and targeted advertisement, it's an all-in-one studio that work seamlessly with each other to get publishers, producers, artists, and companies from A to Z on their projects.

- Help onboarding new staff with new or old devices such as Windows laptops or Apple MacBooks, setting up security, user credentials, and installing necessary software
- Maintain, update, and backup over 40 to 50 devices, including a SNS EVO Server, Xserve, SonicWalls, MacPros, MacBooks, Dell XPS, printers, Cisco VOIP phones and more
- Streamline communication by implementing Slack and its add-on features, such as Zendesk, Google

Drive and others

- Update Cisco phone numbers, directory and information the company changes
- Manage and maintain G-Suite accounts, specifically with File Stream with users as needed
- Perform infrastructure updates to office, from routers, network switches. or firewalls
- Perform on site troubleshooting, break-fix issues, warranty calls, and device updates
- Create original artwork with Photoshop and Illustrator and collaborate with executives on creative direction for album artwork, graphics, posters, and videos
- Maintain and update websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, including adding new artists, updating logos, updating the front-end design, debugging, and testing new features – using Git for version control, ran on a custom WordPress theme
- Create wireframes and mockups for potential website updates
- Help with Office 365 accounts, resetting passwords, updating permission, creating new users and accounts as new staff cycles through
- Create custom videos for YouTube using after effects, uploading 10 to 20 videos a month
- Maintain Dolby 5.1 Certified Studio, used for audio design, movie premiers, client presentations and more
- Work with high-end clients and artists in the studio, setting up audio engineers for in-person or remote recording sessions, wiring microphones, speakers and other recording devices

Enjoy Technology, Inc.

Field & Fulfillment Expert

July 2018 - December 2018

Enjoy is a startup company founded in 2014 by former Apple SVP of Retail, Ron Johnson, that's aiming to change the way products are delivered at home. Offering same-day delivery, they have partnered with different brands like AT&T, Sonos, and Google to provide a full setup experience, answers questions, and carry a mobile inventory with extra products so you can bring the store to the customer.

- Helped launch a brand new Long Island market, being one of the firsts Experts to provide an Enjoy
 experience, streamlining routes and delivery times, providing feedback to HQ, and show that there's a
 need in the market
- Certified in AT&T POS, Sonos Hardware & Software, Magic Leap Virtual Reality, and Google Hardware & Software
- Met weekly and monthly KPIs to show success and help establish a new, growing market in Long Island
- Used G-suite and Slack to communicate effectively, setting up slackbot for urgent information, using Slack for in-house support and speak to the team across the country
- Used an in-house Enjoy app, which allowed us to manage deliveries, inventory, and optimize our logistics for the day or week
- Provided fast and seamless delivery, along with a full set up experience of their newly purchased device
- Set ups consisted of setting up an iPhone to setting up a 5.1 Sonos system across their home, calibrated to the room and provide real surround sound
- Troubleshoot, give recommendations, and followed up with customers on their experience and their new devices
- Performed routine audits of inventory levels to maintain accuracy
- Showed effective time management and prioritization by picking, packing, and fulfilling orders

Apple, Inc.

Genius

March 2018 - June 2018

Apple is one of the biggest tech companies in the world, known for their hardware, software, retail stores, and their exceptional customer service. Being a Genius at Apple means you've mastered all of their products and are now here to push the retail stores to the next level.

- Hands-on repairs on Macs, iPhones, and more
- Found ways to improve and streamline the customer experience for repairs, pick-ups, and appointment times by providing feedback to upper management and HQ, giving suggestions and trying out new methods on the floor
- Trained and developed new staff, set up teams with mentorship roles, attend quarterly meetings and meet metric reviews
- Took appointments for all Apple products, from Apple Watches to Mac Pros, while delivering a fantastic customer experience
- Received and provided feedback to everyone on the team, set up developmental goals for myself and mentorship team members
- Able to stay cool, calm, and collected, deescalate intense situations with customers or peers, and able to make quick in-the-moment decisions
- Apple Certified Macintosh Technician (ACMT)

Apple, Inc.

Technical Expert

October 2017 - March 2018

As a Technical Expert at Apple, you learn all of your hands-on experience with Apple devices such as iPhones. You also take on more leadership over new-hires and start to provide support on the floor.

- Master of iOS and MacOS hardware and software troubleshooting
- Extremely successful in multitasking and juggling multiple customers and still providing high-quality service
- Kept track of daily repairs, set up realistic expectations for customers, and prioritized issues on a case by case basis
- Assessed Repair Room and suggested changes needed to the repair process, which streamlined the way we do repair and shortened our turnaround time
- Apple Certified iOS Technician (ACIT)

Apple, Inc.

Technical Specialist

October 2015 - September 2017

Technical Specialist is where a technician's journey begins. You are first in line tackling appointments, asking customers questions, and figuring out the best way to provide solutions to customers. You assimilate hands-on all the moving parts of an Apple Store and provide the best customer experience possible.

- Took daily appointments of 20 to 30 people in a timely fashion
- Assessed customer's needs, provided options, explained potential solutions, all in a fast-paced, crowded environment
- Created appointments for customers and set up proper expectations
- Reassured customer's when delivering product diagnoses, even if it's bad news, always had multiple potential solutions for customers
- Answered all of customer's questions, recommended what products to buy, and informed them on all the technical specifications of the device

Rockefeller College of Public Affairs & Policies

Web Master & Content Manager

September 2016 - September 2017

A public policy graduate school within the University at Albany which focused on public services and issues and assist the development of government executives. There were multiple departments and websites within the school that needed to be maintained and updated.

- Managed and updated the school's website and individual departments
- Used Dreamweaver and FTP Software such as FileZilla to communicate with the servers and update the website in real time
- Created websites with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and templates on local machines, matching the University's theme and branding policies
- Concurrently worked on multiple projects, supported various director with different goals and gave perspective on how to generate more user interaction
- Updated live calendars on the website using JSON

University at Albany, Advisement Services

Web Developer & Designer

May 2016 – January 2017

My Alma Mater, I started working for the University while still studying and taking classes. The Advisement Services Department is a resource for all students, providing information on all programs, majors, and how to be academically successful.

- Created low-fidelity Wireframes and Mockups of website, aligning them with the school's theme and branding policies
- Used Open Text's Web Site Management tool (formerly Red Dot) to update the website, link pages, and edit the styling
- Started the process of moving over the website's Content Management System and built a website from scratch for the department using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Provided feedback on what should be on the department's home page, what users are mostly interested, and what's the best way to display information to students